所以我对了解sha-256的哈希函数是如何工作的感到很感兴趣，
所以我创建了这个小脚本，它可以动态的显示数据的哈希过程，
这样我就可以看到它是如何工作的。
这个脚本只是在后台对字符串ABC进行哈希处理。
我想在这个视频中逐步解释sha-256哈希函数是如何工作的，
我会从基本知识开始，然后在这个基础之上慢慢拓展，以便我们最终能够理解整个哈希函数机制，
然后我们就能理解sha-256是如何工作的。
请耐心等待，我会从基本知识开始解释。
首先，哈希函数是什么？
哈希函数接收一些数据，并为你提供一个唯一的，更短的那些数据的摘要或指纹，这就是它的全部功能，
或者说它把数据打乱，然后为你提供一个更短的摘要。
所以，如果我对数据进行微小的修改，你会得到两个完全不同的结果，
所以世界上的每一个数据都有自己独一无二的哈希摘要。
你可以对字符串进行这样的操作，也可以对文件进行这样的操作。
我这里有一个文件，写入"hello there"，我保存它，然后获取这个文件的sha-256摘要。
如果我对文件稍作修改，再来一次，我得到了一个完全不同的结果，这很酷。
这使我可以检查一个文件何时发生了改变。
而比特币中使用的哈希函数，就是利用了这样的特性，
你可以对一些数据进行哈希处理，然后进行微小的调整，它会产生一些极其不同的结果，这就是挖矿的一部分。
but the way well that's I use hash functions we're in Bitcoin and the fact that and you can hash something some data and I make a tiny adjustment and it produces some wildly different results makes up a part of mining
同时，需要注意的是，你无法真正控制这个哈希函数的结果，
what's important to note as well is that you can't control really what comes out to this hash function
it scrambles data in a way that you can't really predict what the result is gonna
be all you can do is hash it and see
what it is so if I wanted this to start
with
you know Tenet's um I can't do that
all I have to do is just keep trying
different pizza pieces of data and
hopefully I'll find one that starts with
ten A's so this is how a mining
basically works
so what miner will do if you've ever
been interested in Bitcoin is they want
to add blocks of transactions onto the
blockchain but they need to work to be
able to do this so what they do they'll
start by getting some transactions from
the memory pool which is like a waiting
area of the latest transactions on the
network the orcish bring these together
into a site into a block and for that
block they'll construct a block header
which basically summarizes all the data
inside the block and it's this block
header let's rehash so this is the data
that we're gonna put into the hash
function but there's no bit of space
here for the nonce which is short for a
number used once and so what I'm gonna
do we're going to increment that along
with the rest the block header and
continue hashing it over and over again
because the goal is we want to get a
hash result the starts with a certain
number of zeros always below a certain
value basically so if I take that back
header and keep changing this non-spell
you as you can see here again lots of
different hash results so this is a
miner basically trying to mine a block
and what they'll do they'll be doing
this as fast as possible to try and get
one hash digest or result that is starts
with the number of zeros that was in the
target this lofty take quite a while for
to finish this is running very slowly
but luckily this is a block there's been
mined before so I know what the the
nonce value is that works and so if I
could run it again but start the nonce a
bit higher up and you'll see that this
nonce value here purely randomly
produces a hash digest that starts with
this many zeros which is below the
target and so this block has been mined
and can be added on to the blockchain
the miners you know you can't force this
to happen all you can do is just take
that block header for your block and how
fast
Hacha as fast as possible to try and
find a nonce and that's lucky enough to
give you a result that's below the
target so this creates like a
network-wide competition that no one can
force or take control of and it protects
the transactions they're already in the
blockchain but us on the side my care
about today is how this hash function
works how do I get from my name Greg or
the string ABC ABC how do I end up with
this result from ABC and that's going to
show you now so sorry for the lengthy
introduction but hopefully was
interesting first of all I'll start with
the real basics of some operations that
char 256 users so the first one is
called a shift right so char 256 works
on bits ones and zeros all data can we
move represented in bits and it operates
on chunks of 32 bits which we refer to
as a word started a word they just say
two bits so a shift right it shifts the
bits over a number of positions so
that's a 32 right a 32 bit shift here
but you just shift shift shift bits to
the right next of all we have a right
rotation or rotation right which is very
similar to a right shift but instead of
a shift in the bits off and then never
come back again it moves them over onto
the left-hand side to create this
rotational bitwise operation or a
circular
right shift
next we have this operation called
exclusive-or which basically it produces
a one if one of the two bits you've been
put into it ro ro 1 is a 1 there's only
one one let me just show you 2 lot 0 so
there that's our 1 then both of these
over 1 so he only wants one one
exclusive or so that's a zero but again
just one one yeah one so what this means
is that for multiple bits you can sort
of merge them together to get a fair
representation or balanced
representation of all the bits that
you're putting in so here for example
and I'm doing multiple XOR operations on
three bits so the first two zero and
zero that's a zero cuz only expects one
to be 1 and then 0 and 1 is a 1 so we
end up with a one like so so may be
easier if I just show you we have an
animation so this is X or in different
combinations of bits and showing you the
result so like I said it gives you a
balanced represent balanced
representation of three input input bits
for any 3 given bits half a time you
only get one half the time you're gonna
get at 0 I hope that makes some sense
lastly we have one called well just
normal addition so insert integer
integer addition so this these are just
numbers represented in binary we add
them together and ask just addition so
it's like adding you know any two normal
integers together but we're representing
it in binary one thing to note though is
after adding doing it addition we take
it modulus to 232 so basically that sort
constrains the result to be in within a
32-bit word
so if we add multiple words together and
the result is greater than 32 bits this
mod 2 2 3 2 keeps it within
to emit range so these are the building
blocks of the sha-256 hash function if
you understand these then the rest isn't
so hard now using those rotational
functions we can combine them together
to create these sort of compound
movements of bits so this one here is
called a lowercase Sigma Sigma 0 all it
does it does these rotations 7 18 and 3
to this single word and then axles them
together to get this result here so 1 +
1 is 1 then 1 + 1 is 0 0 so I'm like so
and it's called Sigma not for any
particular reason just because you
wanted to give a name to these compound
movements or operations on bits yah I
also have one called Sigma one lowercase
Sigma one exactly the same just
different number of rotations and a
different number of shifts third one is
uppercase Sigma 0 again different number
rotations and they XOR them together
like that and then we have the fourth
and final rotational compound movement
upper case Sigma 1 and there's you know
6 and 11 and 25 rotations there next
wasn't together so they're all very
similar Theory difference is the
lowercase Sigma functions use make use
of this shift right so some bits are
lost off the end here whereas the upper
case Sigma just do full there's full
rotations three times on the input word
lastly we have two more functions that
don't use rotations we have one called
choice which uses the first input to
determine whether to take the input from
the second or third word so if it's a 1
it takes the Y and if it's a 0
it takes the Zed so here one takes the
101 takes the one in last year o 0 takes
the Zed and that's there so it uses the
X word it takes three inputs to choose
the bit of the second or third word
that's what's called choice anyway
lastly we have majority easier to
explain it just the result is the
majority of three bits so majority here
is one sauce one majority he here is
zero zero so these are the six functions
that are used throughout the sha-256
hash function right one last thing
before I actually get to the hash
function I just need to show you some
constants that char 256 users so these
constants are ultimately just some
random looking bits to help mix up the
message that we put into the hash
function so where do these come from if
we look here oops it's taken the cube
root of the first 64 prime numbers so
this is the cube root of 13 well
actually this is a cube root cube root
of 19 gets you this result here but the
cube root of a prime number or square
root of a prime number gives you an
irrational result so this fraction is
irrational it'll go on forever and it's
pretty pretty random looking so it makes
you a good source for a constant because
you know if we chose the constant
specifically they could have we could
have designed char 256 with the backdoor
that by using this or publicly known
random looking bits the cube roots and
prime numbers we get these
nice-lookin constants the fairly random
looking to help us to mix up our
messages so this is done for the first
64 prime numbers and that gives us 64
constants that we're going to work with
you in the hash function all these
random bits here so now we can finally
get into the sha-256 hash algorithm so
one going to here and go into hash the
string ABC and I'm gonna step through
each part of the hash function alright
first of all so we've got ABC that's a
string as you might have you might have
as you might have noticed the hash
function works on individual bits the
ones and zeroes of data and so all data
can be represented in ones and zeros so
this string here a B and C each of these
letters has their own sort correspondent
number in the ASC III table ASCII table
so a is 97 beam is C 99 and then we can
convert these numbers then into their
binding we have binary representation so
this is what ABC looks like in binary
and this is what we're gonna put into
the hash function
so before we start hashing it we first
of all need to Pat it out because the
hash function likes to hash data in
chunks of 512 bits at a time so this is
only 24 bits of data so we need to
paddle out with zeros basically to get
it up to 512 bits but before we do that
but before the zeros we put a 1 after
the message sort of like as a separator
between the message and the zeros then
we add in the zeros but as you notice
here this is a little bit short of 512
because we're leaving 64 bits at the end
space because in those last 64 bits we
encode the length of the message so the
message here is 24 bits and this is how
you represent 24 in binary so the last
64 bits here however much it was is
reserved for the length of the message
or the size of the message inside the
padding
there we are we've padded our message up
to 512 bits which is what posh function
wants to hash if our message was
slightly larger than 512 it would've
been padded up to the next nearest
multiple of 512 bits which we would have
been 1,024 bits poorest Cosby is a
multiple of 512 so once we padded it we
then split it up into 500 512 bit blocks
so because this is already 512 bits we
just have one message block but if it
was bigger we might have you know 2 3 4
message blocks from the original message
so this message block is what we're
gonna put into the hash function
we've just prepared our message to be
hashed so the first we need to do is we
need to create a message schedule from
each message block so this is the
message block and the message schedule
is basically taking that and splitting
up into 32-bit words so we just use the
data in the block to construct the first
16 words of the message schedule however
this message schedule actually needs to
be 64 words long so we need to extend it
or expand it another 48 words up to 60
up to 64 so the way we do that is we use
some words already in the mess schedule
to create the next words in the schedule
so this sixteenth word here it uses the
- 16th word in a schedule along with the
minus 15 minus seventh and then minus
two weird but on the this word we do a
lowercase Sigma zero rotation to it and
on this word we do it our case Sigma one
rotation as you can see these are just
zero again because the rotation is just
rotating a load of zeroes and XOR in
them together which gives you always get
to 0 and so it's quite boring and that's
why this
new word in the master schedule is
exactly the same as this because that
added to that to that to that gives you
this so it's pretty boring but as you
move down the meta schedule you'll see
that we're expanding it and again lots
of new bits being extended into the
schedule so these rotational functions
here use the existing existing data in
the message block and sort of to fuse
them and expand the message schedule
with lots of new bits so there we are
that's the last word in the message
schedule just to show you how that works
a bit more visually so it's an animation
like I said it takes existing words and
then rotates them and then add them
together to create the new words in the
schedule
there we are and that's very creative
the 63 or 64 'the word in the schedule
there we are know you've prepared her
Metis schedule extended the message
block this is what we're going to feed
into the main hash function along with
those constants I mentioned mentioned
earlier so like I said this is now we
move into the compression part of the
hash function and this is the real heart
of the hash function this is where all
the bits get we all squish together and
overnight on top of each other to create
the final metal message digest but first
of all we need to initialize the hash
values in this compression function so
these are called
state registers or working variables and
there's eight slots the data to go into
for the words to fall into and these are
initialized similar to the constants
using the square root this time of prime
numbers so that'll give you a nice
little a rational fraction part here or
some random bits to initialize the hash
with take the fractional part multiply
it by two 232 because I'll give you 32
bits with the data and this is the
result of that in an integer integer for
convert that to binary and there we have
our initial hash values so every single
piece of data that your hash will start
out looking like this and then we'll use
the message schedule to modify it so now
we're going to go into the compression
function we're gonna take that message
schedule from our first message block
and we're gonna compress it into these
stage registers so we take the first
word so we're gonna do this for every
single word in the message schedule this
is the first word and this is the first
word in the constants so before we
modify any of this we first of all need
to create two temporary words look at
the complex bar break it don't know
so let me just show you an animation
this is the first temporary wood what
you do you take the choice of these
three EF and G that gives you this then
you take a uppercase Sigma one rotation
of e like that then you just take H and
then add all these three together along
with the word in the message schedule or
the current word in the master schedule
and the current constant and that gives
you this temporary word here that's the
first one and then the second temporary
word is a bit simpler but also quite
similar it takes the majority over the
first three a B and C let's give you
that and then you do a application Sigma
0 rotation of the first word in the
state registers and then you others
together and you have t2 so we're gonna
use these in the moment to update the
data in this in these hash values right
so now we're gonna get into the cool
part so I'm gonna do one round of
compression so first of all we move all
the words in the state registers down
one start leaving a space here inside a
and we lose the last one
into a we put t1 plus t2 and that gives
you that and then into e we add t1 so
move everything down put a new word into
a and update e and so this process
repeats for every single word in the
message schedule so we have 63 words six
three constants so we went through each
of those and do the compression for
every single word in our master schedule
so I'll keep doing this and this is
carries on for every word
nearly there and then we get to the
final word update the stage registers
one more time and there we have you've
just compressed every single word in a
master schedule into these state
registers the last part then of this
compression for this message block is to
take the initial hash values you started
with and add on the end result of the
compression so there we are there we
have the hash values for the first
message block so this process would
repeat for every single message block so
for the next message block we were
quitting at the master schedule and then
read to a compression using these values
as the initial hash values and this
happens over and over again for every
single message block so every message
block is compressed onto the existing
hash values and once you've done that
for every single message block then
you'll have some final values left in
the state registers or some pine and
final hash value and then the final hash
then is if we convert each of these
words into hexadecimal and then
concatenate them together we end up with
the final message digest and that is our
how sha-256 works