这个演讲将解释你需要知道的关于比特币密钥和地址的所有信息。
你可能听过像私钥、公钥和地址这样的东西，
我将在这个演讲中解释它们的来源和工作原理。
我快速概述这个演示中会包含什么内容。
我将从基础知识开始，
解释密钥的来源和工作方式，
并对它们的工作方式进行一个基本的概述。
我将讲解每个密钥是如何生成的，
你有一个私钥，
然后从那里生成一个公钥，
这两个是你在比特币中使用的主要密钥，
类似于密码和账号。
你有所谓的数字签名，
这些被用来证明你拥有一个公钥，
就像用于签署交易一样。
我将解释这些是如何工作的。
我会讲解地址是如何工作的，
地址基本上就像公钥的一个更漂亮或对用户更友好的版本。
我将解释它们是如何工作的，
以及它们是如何连接在一起的。
在最后，我将通过一些代码和例子，
来展示你如何生成自己的私钥、公钥和地址。
这个演讲主要是讲解，
不涉及太多的代码，
最后可能会有一些关于数字签名的详细解释，
但只要你对它的工作方式有一个大概了解就可以了。
我将开始，
这也是为什么比特币和其他货币被称为加密货币，
因为这个私钥和公钥的被称为加密，
使用了密码学，
所以我们称他们为加密货币，
这是交易系统或比特币所有权的基础。
它们连接在一起并共享一个名为区块链的文件
快进到我们上次停止的地方，
正如你从我上次的演讲中看到的那样，
这就是比特币网络，
比特币网络就是一群计算机。
互相连接在一起，
并共享一个名为区块链的文件
当你想进行比特币交易时，
你想向某人发送一些比特币，
你只需要一行描述移动的数据即可进行这样的交易，
比特币从这个人到那个人。
当你希望将这个交易添加到区块链中时，
你会将交易插入到网络上的一个节点中，
他们会在他们的内存池中快速存储这个交易。
然后他们会将交易传递给他们所连接的节点，
如此反复，
直到交易在网络上每个节点的内存池中。
之后，所有这些节点都会尝试竞争将他们内存池中的交易添加到区块链上。
这个过程被称为挖矿，
让我们假设这个人或者这个矿工，
他能够将内存池中的交易添加到区块链上。
所以一旦有一个交易块被添加进去，
他们会将该区块传递给连接的节点，
然后将其添加到他们的区块链中，
如此反复，
直到每个人的区块链副本都更新了最新的交易区块。
然后这个人可以查看区块链，
看到所有权已经从这个人转移到了那个人。
在上一次的演讲中，
我解释了这些交易在内部看起来是什么样子的。
你可以把交易想象成这样：
区块链充满了所有的交易数据，
但如果你将其拆开看，
就像看到很多不同批次，
不同大小的比特币。
当你进行交易时，
你需要进入到区块链中，
选择一个特定的比特币批次，
比如说这个窗口是一个10的批次，
然后你会从那里取出那批比特币，
创建一个新的批次。
发送一批新的比特币就像从旧的批次中创建一个新的批次。
然后你会将那批比特币发送到网络中，
这个交易大约需要两个比特币，
然后创建一个新的进入网络，
然后这个新的批次会进入到一个内存池，
然后进入到区块链中。
然后当你查看区块链时，
这个新的批次会出现在这个新的区块中，
而我们用过的整个批次将会被灰掉，
因为它已经被消费掉了。
我一直在称它们为批次，
但实际上它们被称为输出，
当你在交易中使用一个输出时，
它被称为输入。
所以你可以把区块链想象为充满了输出，
它们只是被选择出来，
然后从它们中创建出新的输出。
这一切都很好，
但是你如何拥有这些比特币批次呢？
每一批比特币都有一个锁，
每个想要使用比特币的人都有自己的一套密钥，
你有一个私钥，就像你的密码，
和你的公钥，就像你的账户号码。
所以，当你想要进行交易，
如果这批比特币属于你，
那么你就可以使用你的私钥来解锁它们，
然后从那里你可以创建一个新的批次。
如果你想把比特币发送给这个人，
他们会给你他们的公钥，
使用这个公钥，
你可以在这个输出，这批比特币上创建一个锁，
这批比特币被锁定到这个人的公钥，
因为他们把它给了我们。
如果他们想要把这批10个比特币的比特币发送给别人，
他们就可以使用他们的私钥来解锁它们，
然后发送，所以这就是一个典型的交易。
通过使用这些密钥——私钥和公钥，
这就相当于拥有一个账号和密码。
我再次强调，
一旦你构建了这个交易，
你就不再拥有一批比特币的所有权，
而是创建了一批新的比特币，
锁定给另一个人。
然后你会将这个交易发送到网络中，
最终这个交易会被记录到区块链上，
比特币的批次将会更新。
这个批次已经被花费掉了，
它被灰色标记，不能再次被花费，
新的批次会出现在新的区块中，
属于另一个人。
如果你想使用比特币，
你只需要拥有自己的一套密钥。
如果你只是想接收别人的比特币，
你就需要创建并拥有自己的一套密钥才能使用比特币。
那么，这些密钥是从哪里来的呢？
我可以告诉你它们不是从哪里来的。
没有人可以控制比特币，
有一本书或一台电脑充满了密钥，
你可以要求他给你一个私钥和一个公钥。
没有人你需要问他给你一个公钥。
这可能是银行的情况，如果你去银行，
你必须要求某人给你自己的账号和密码，
以便使用他们的服务发送和接收资金。
但在比特币中，
我们没有中央控制点，
因为比特币是去中心化的，
没有一个人可以控制谁可以使用它。
所以，这不是比特币的工作方式。
那么，如果没有人控制密钥或账号，
你可以要求他们给你，
那么它们是从哪里来的呢？
答案是，我们自己生成私钥和公钥。
我们不需要问其他人，
或者我们需要从哪里获取这些密钥，
我们实际上自己创建它们。
我们创建，我们就像我们是任何人一样，
基本上任何人都可以使用比特币，
因为我们创建我们自己的账号和密码。
我希望这个介绍能让你们都理解，
现在我将进入创建、生成和使用这些密钥的基础知识。
these keys so how do you generate your
own set of keys to be able to send
receive and send bitcoins well first of
all you start with a private key and the
simplest way or well the only way to
generate your own private key to start
out with it's just to generate a random
number so like so you'll just generate a
random number this is obviously a very
small number bitcoin private keys are
much bigger numbers but this is just
just to show you and then from there you
need your public key so if a private key
is your password the public key is like
your account number but obviously
because there's no one given out these
sets of keys when we generate our public
key we want to have a connection between
our private key and our public key so
that when we use them well so that's
what we can use our private key to
unlock bitcoins because they're
connected so how would you create a
connection between a public key and a
private key well what you do is you just
used use some mathematics to derive your
public key from your private key so you
basically take your private key put it
through some mathematical functions and
then that will give you a public key and
so this public key is connected to your
private key through mathematics that's
where the connection is so again when
you generates a set of keys to be used
in Bitcoin you start your private key
it's just a random number and then from
that you create your public key or your
account number which is just a
mathematically connected number that's
connected to your private key and that
is how you generate your own set of keys
so that you can receive bitcoins from
other people and then send them on to
other people also
so anyone can do this anyone can
generate their own set of keys to be
used in Bitcoin so that's the basics
done now I'm going to start with this
private key because generating your own
set of keys it all starts with the
private key so move this across there we
go like I said your private key is just
generating a random number and this
random number can be between anywhere
from 1 to this number now this is a very
very large number but as long as you
generate a number between 1 and this
value it's a valid private key or you've
valid starting points your valid
password to use Bitcoin this is often
referred to as a 256 big 256 bit number
and this just describes the size of it
how big the number is and that comes
from basically computers they store data
you know you have kilobytes and bytes
and megabytes while a bit is the
smallest you know unit of data that a
computer can hold and all that is is a 0
or 1 and so all the data on your
computer is ultimately stored in a
sequence of zeros and ones so same thing
for numbers when you want to store
numbers on a computer they are also
stored in zeros on one zeros and ones so
if you want to store numbers start out
when starting out with 0 you can store
that quite easily
in bits by using the number 0 the number
1 similar thing you can just use the bit
1 but then for the number 2 you've run
out of characters that you can store
this data in so you just add another bit
in so in binary or in a sequence of bits
the number 2 is stored as a 1 and then a
0 and then again 3 1 1 but then you've
run out of options again so you need
another bit to store a bigger number
like so so this goes on and on so the
bigger the number
becomes the more bits you need to be
able to represent it or store it on a
computer so who carried on doing this
and you had 256 bits lined up together
and you put ones in all of them then
that would be able to store this number
here so that's why it's called a 256 bit
number
it's basically what a computer the
largest number a computer can hold in
256 bits worth of data and that's also
the same as saying 2 to the power of 256
because we have two options for each
each block here and sock might be either
be a 0 or 1 and if you do that 256 times
so ^ 2056 that gives you this number
here 2 ^ 256 which is a very big number
so then the question now is what if
someone generates the same private key
as me this obviously seems like a bit of
a crude mechanism for generating you own
private password to be able to use
Bitcoin well the answer is that this
number is so large that nobody is going
to generate the same private key as you
to illustrate that let's say this is the
known visible universe this number here
this is the number of atoms in this
known visible universe so as you can see
which is 10 to the power of 78 as you
can see this 256 bit number here is not
too far off from the number of atoms in
universe so you just have to trust me
when I say that because this is number
is so large I mean it doesn't
particularly look large here because I
can display it on a screen but it is
unbelievably large and the fact that
it's so large means that 2 different
people are not going to generate the
same number
and that's just how big it is and that's
so secure it is and this has been
working fine in Bitcoin no problems
there's been no known case of anyone
generating the same private key or not I
know of anyway and if there was it would
be big news but like I said it's a very
big number so private key you just
generate a number up to between one and
this value here just generated and I'll
give you your private key something
sensitive huh okay right so private key
just a random number we've just
generated from that we can now get our
public key so like I said without public
key it needs to be connected to our
private key somehow because we need our
account number to be connected to our
password so the way we do that is we use
some mathematics and there's a
particular type of mathematics we use
though and that mathematics uses this
thing here which is called an elliptic
curve you have lots of different
elliptic curves this is just in this
illustration of one but the what
particular one used in Bitcoin is called
sec p 2 5 6 k 1 so like I said there are
lots of different elliptic curves but
this is the particular one the
particular shape that Bitcoin users and
so to get your public key from this
private key you often do you have to do
what's called elliptic curve
multiplication the reason well but why
we we are using this limit elliptic
curve for them apparent later on so just
bear with me now while I show you how
this elliptic curve multiplication works
so with the SEC P 2 5 6 K 1 it comes
with a starting point and to do
multiplication
this is going to be a simplified
explanation but it's basically this is
called G blow away the starting point or
the generated point but for
multiplication
it's basically draw a tangent on the
cave starting by a tangent at the point
on the curve so we'll start at this
generate generate a point here and one
of the properties of this elliptic curve
is that if you draw a tangent on it then
it's always going to intersect the curve
at one other point and that's just one
of the properties of this particular
type of curve and that's why we use it
so have you done that when it intersects
this point you take that point called
the intersect and then you just invert
it and take the opposite point on the
curve from this point here from the
intersect I'm going to take this point
this point here is like doing one round
of multiplication so if this was one G
this would be 2 G and then again if you
want do another round of multiplication
draw another tangent and it will
intersect another point in the curve and
that will give you well then you take
the inverse of that and that will give
you you know another point on the curve
and is a second round of multiplication
this is a bit simplified but this is
basically how it works so again when you
want to multiply again you just take
another tangent again at the point in
the curve and so on and so on so
basically when you do an elliptic curve
multiplication you're drawn all these
tangents and taking the inverse points
but ultimately ultimately what's
happening you are bouncing around this
curve in a particular way like this so
what you do then you're bouncing on the
curve this many times
so you're bouncing on the key of private
key times so obviously I don't end there
but you'll keep doing this until you've
done it
private key times when she's done that
maybe I when she done last you'll end up
with a point on the curve and this point
on the curve is the public key so there
are many many many points on this curve
basically about as many points in this
cave as there are private keys so once
you've got that public so basically like
I said this final resting point on the
curve after bouncing around it this many
times gives you a public key and to be
precise your public key is just the X&Y
coordinates of this point so there we
are nasty X and as to why put them
together like this and that is your
public key one of the reasons why we use
this elliptic curve is because one of
the properties of it is it this
multiplication is what's called a
trapdoor function which means that you
can easily do private key multiplication
well to multiplication using private key
and I give you can bounce on the curve
but going backwards
taking this point on the curve and
figuring out what the private key was
from that is very difficult while it
hasn't been solved yet no one knows how
to take a public key or a point on the
curve and figure out what the private
key was the number we multiplied the
generator point by it's a bit hard to
explain why I think this elliptic curve
deserves a video of its own but all I
can say is that you're doing a lot of
modulus modulus mathematics and so
enough information gets thrown away
whilst doing this multiplication stuff
so you can't just just very difficult to
go backwards and that's why we we rely
on this little curve to basically
protect our public keys and private keys
and this if want to find out more about
why can go backwards it's called the
elliptic curve discrete logarithm
problem but there we go
so we've started with a random number
we've done some elliptic curve
mathematics and we've got a point on the
curve and that is our public key so this
is the mathematical connection this
through this elliptic curve we have a
mathematical connection from our private
key to our public key yes yes so when
you have different caves and this one's
called SEC P you have this one and so
that comes with a particular G generator
point yeah yessum okay cryptography
thing yeah so you can have 10 kids but
it kind uses this particular curve and
these particular parameters so there we
are so that's creating our public key so
now we've got you just generated our
private key and a public key we can
start using Bitcoin so if you want some
people to send us bitcoins we just give
them our public key like so so they've
got a copy of our public key and then
they can unlock any batteries a bitcoins
that they own create a new batch and put
a lock on it and lock this batch of
bitcoins to our public key so when we
want to send bitcoins then the ones
we've received they've been locked to
our public key that we've given away we
just use what we create the transaction
first we want to send them and then we
use our private key to unlock this lock
or basically prove that we created this
public key or that we have the
mathematical connection to this public
key and no one else no one else should
have it so how do we prove that
we created this public key how can we
show that we have the private key that
this public key was created from well a
bad way to do it would be to or one way
of doing it that would be bad
would be just to put your private key
into this transaction into the
transaction you've created so well that
means is anyone could look at this
private key in public key and say okay
this public this person obviously has
this private key because they've given
it to us and they can they can see the
mathematical connection for themselves
they can do the elliptic curve
multiplication and get the same public
key and that proves that we created this
public key but the problem is when this
transaction goes out into the Bitcoin
network it's gonna be in all of these
nodes and so anyone can see this
publicly exposed private key and if they
can see it then what they can do they
can take that public private key and if
there are any other bitcoins locked to
the same public key as this one they can
just copy our private key and basically
take all of the bitcoins or outputs that
have been locked to this public key
before so the last thing we want to do
is give away this private key so that
wouldn't work so what can we do instead
we need to put something here
in this transaction that proves that we
created this public key and we need to
put something here the only we can
create that no one else can put here to
unlock this batch of bitcoins it's what
do we do well we use our private key
again but instead of putting our actual
private key into this transaction data
you create what's called a signature now
these signatures are very handy because
they are created from the private key
and they can actually still prove that
we created this public key
but the good thing is well one it
doesn't give out a way our private key
and also they only work for the
transaction that we're signing so if
someone else sees a signature and we've
got other bitcoins locked to this public
key they can't just look at this
signature take it and put it into this
transaction or transaction they create
because that won't work because this
signature only works for the one
transaction that we are creating so you
could think of the signature as a sort
of special one-time private key that we
use to unlock batches of bitcoins does
that make sense
I cover the details in a moment but as
long as that makes some sense that's
just the very basics of signatures so
we've got a private key a public key but
now we need to figure out how to create
Dignitas digital signatures you know how
can we create this thing here at the
ball and lock this transaction or the
batch of bitcoins for this transaction
without giving away our private key so
that's one of Kevin OH
so a signature we need to create a
signature I'm gonna run through this a
little quickly and I'm gonna cover the
absolute basics don't worry if it
doesn't make complete sense on the first
attempt just as long as you get the gist
of it that's fine it involves some
mathematics so let's move this all other
way
maybe I'll just move everything of the
way but I don't that down here now we
need to create a signature there's two
steps to create a signature and it
involves the use of this elliptic curve
again no surprises that's why we use the
elliptic curve in the first place
because we can use it again to create
signatures so the first part had this
two-step process for creating a
signature is you need a random part so
what you do is you start out by Chariton
a very big random number
and doing some elliptic curve
multiplication again just like we did
earlier and that would give you a random
point on the curve so this is very
similar to what we did earlier we just
took a private key and create a public
key this is the exact same thing but
we're just using a random number that's
going to be used for this one-time
signature for this transaction and so
this random point on the curve that we
generate is called our or what
specifically more specifically we just
need the x value for it
secondly using that random point or the
x value which is just a number we
multiply that but our private key which
again is just a number and then we add
in what's called a message some thing we
want to sign so the thing we want to
create a signature for is this
transaction here so we basically put
that transaction into here as the
message and this is all just a bunch of
data but just we don't put the actual
full data in there what we do we just
hash it and put that the hash of the
data in there but basically we've got
the random part this x value we multiply
that with a private key and then we just
add in the fingerprint for the
transaction we want to sign and then we
just write all that then by our again so
the key thing here really is that we've
got a random point in the cave and we've
got this special number here that
contains a mix of our private key and
the transaction we want the signature to
work for and this is called s so as you
can see the private key and the
transaction data is in there but it's
all jumbled up
so if and we could look at this s value
but they won't be able to see what our
actual private key is because we've used
this R and what not to scramble it up a
little bit but it's all in there so the
signature then is just these two parts
so you put the R in there and you put
the S value in there
so the are just around a point in the
cave the s is a special number that
contains our private key and the
transaction data we want to sign and
that is our signature signature is just
an R and an espalier so move out there
that's the first part then go on through
this again today it will be awesome so
the first part you mentioned was we have
the same gene
generate a random number yes so this is
just a random number yeah you just
missed it yeah and we multiply that
random number with G so we keep hopping
around the curve until you get to a
point just after that and at this point
like our public or private he has not
come into the picture this is random
okay yeah let's go to number two now
okay so we take X from the our with our
private key so we again be hopping
around no sorry this is uh this is not
elliptic curve multiplication this is
just pure mathis normal mathematics so
if you remember our private key is just
a number and this x-value is also just a
number so we just so we just do normal
mathematics so it's not elliptical
multiplication okay okay okay and the
message is basically our what was that
again yeah just the transaction data so
by putting the transaction data into
here and that means this signature will
only work for this particular
transaction and obviously the private
key is here just to prove that we own
this public key
like and from the previous video this is
the transaction data without the single
yes that's correct
so you take all this thing it yeah so
you take all the signatures out and then
you put then you hatch the data and put
it into here yes good good memory yep
and we so these are values serve to help
to scramble up this you know our private
key basically okay yeah so that is a
signature created house two parts random
random point on the cave and a special
number derived from using our private
key now we'll see why this works now why
did we create these two things for the
signature well when we put where we send
this transaction data or this whole
transaction into the Bitcoin network
every single node on the network is
going to various verify that this is a
this is a valid transaction so they're
gonna take this signature and they want
to fight and they want to be able to say
okay this signature could only have been
created by the person who owns the
private key that this public key was
created from so they need to verify that
to make sure that their signature works
always created from this particular
private key so how can they do that they
haven't got the private key or they've
got these two values the R and the s
value but the s value has been created
from this private key so how do they do
that well first of all they take this R
value that it given them and this is the
while they just start with that and
again this is a two step process for
them as well
first of all
they do some normal mathematics they
just multiply the hash of the
transaction data without our value and
that will give them just a very big
number and so what they do without very
big number on this first step after
multiplying these two values together
they'll start at this generator point
and they'll do elliptic curve
multiplication using this big number
they've multiplied starting at G and
they'll bounce around it and that would
give them this first point on the curve
second of all they'll do some more
normal multiplication again you'll just
do s times R so they'll just take this s
value multiply it by this R value and
then starting this time at the public
key they will bounce around the key of
this many times so that bounce on the
key of this many times and I'll give
them a second point on the curve and now
the magic part here is if all three of
these points on the curve line up then
that means that this signature is valid
so with elliptic curves if you draw a
line through two points on the curve
just like a tangent will always
intersect one other point on the curve
if you draw a line through two points on
the curve that will always intersect one
other point on the curve as well so by
generating these two points on the curve
using these two values that we that we
have been given along with the public
key and the transaction data we can
generate at these two points on the
curve and if they all line up then the
signature is valid so what that means is
that if someone tampers with the
transaction data so we give them as
transaction data and the signature and
then they try and send the bitcoins to
their address they tamper with you know
the transaction data that means that
this value will be different and so when
they generate the first point that'll be
different and they won't all line up
so the signature won't work then so that
protects this transaction data from
being altered
similarly if someone tries to create a
signature to spend our bitcoins using a
private key of their own you know not
the one that we created the public key
from so a different private key
altogether that means that when they
generate this s value that be completely
different and if that s value is
different than this number here is gonna
be different so when we do the elliptic
curve multiplication starting from the
public key this point is gonna be
different again and the points won't
line up so this is a very basic overview
of how digital signatures work and if
all you understand is that private keys
and public keys are connected through
elliptic curves and the reason we use
elliptic curves is because we can create
these signatures and other people can
verify them doing some elliptic a of
mathematics and these are the special
properties of elliptic curves so again
just to summarize like I said and you
just take a private key you do elliptic
eight of mathematics multiplication
together public key and then you give
that public key to other people and
they'll put that or they'll lock up a
batch of bitcoins to that public key but
then from there we need to where we want
to send them on to other people we want
to send them on we need to prove that we
are the creators of this public key so
what we do we take our private key
create a signal signature which again
involves some elliptic curve mathematics
and then we give them that signature and
then they can do some verification to
verify that we created this signature
from the correct private key and they do
that by taking this public key and the
signature and also the data and they
generates three points on the curve and
if they line up and if they line up then
that signature works
and again if someone doesn't use the
right private key
they won't line up or if someone alters
with the transaction data they won't
line up either again so it's a bit magic
this whole process but ultimately it's
all mathematics and if what will you
take away from this a few slides it's
just that this elliptic curve
mathematics is very good for
cryptography and for you know creating
account numbers and passwords and then
being able to prove that you own the
account number without ever given the
password away which is very clever so
this is called elliptic curve
cryptography and it's very very useful
and without it we would not be able to
send and receive bitcoins safely without
having a person in control of all the
sets of keys so this means through this
elliptic curve cryptography we can
generate our own account numbers and
passwords to be able to send and receive
bitcoins which is very very handy and
again like I said at the start this
video crypto this is why Bitcoin another
and currencies I get are called crypto
currencies because they use cryptography
as the backbone for the ownership of
these batches of bitcoins
so let me just move all this back to
here so that is private key public key
and the signatures done so this is the
basics of sending or receiving and
receiving bitcoins
in a Bitcoin just these set keys and
cretins digital signatures to prove that
you own the public part of them so from
there you've probably heard of addresses
what our address is well addresses are
just basically prettier versions of the
public key more user-friendly versions
of the public key so originally or you
can still do this in Bitcoin you can
just generate a private key and a public
key for yourself give that public key to
other people they will lock up bitcoins
for you you know to that public key and
then you can use that private key to
create a signature and send them on but
this all works well and it's fine
if someone looks at this public key they
can't figure out like I said before
while the private key is because you
can't go backwards through this I
diptych hear of multiplication you can
go this way we can't go that way but
what it does mean is that this is not
known to have been solved at this moment
in time and it doesn't look like
anyone's gonna find a solution for going
backwards for the through the elliptic
curve but it does mean that if it was
ever broken then your public keys while
your bitcoins can be stolen I mean
there's no risk no one can see this
happening for the foreseeable future but
it does mean that this public key is
like a sitting duck waiting to be broken
if listen diptych if can be broken so in
Bitcoin we like to use a bit more
security how can we not have to just
rely on this elliptic curve discrete
logarithm problem to protect our
bitcoins
so the solution tart is and what we do
is we just a hash this public key twice
through tooth through two different
hashing functions the first one first
one is a sha-256 which is when you
should be familiar with from mining and
then also a second one is used called
Reich MD 160 so what it says is like
double hashing through different through
two different hashing functions the
public key and then what you do then
you'll give that hashed version of the
public key to the people instead of the
standard public key so it's like a
scrambled version of this public key you
give that to other people and then
they'll actually put these in the locks
so what that means is whilst this hashed
version of the public key is in the lock
if someone wants to go all the way back
to get to your private key instead of
just going back from the public key and
trying to go through backwards through
the and it to cave which you can't do
but that's the only here it'll jump over
if you want to figure out your private
key from this hashed version of the
public key you have to go basically you
have to break the ripe empty hash
function which no one is done then you
also have to be able to go backwards
with a sha-256 hash function regional is
done and after doing that I'll give you
the private public key then using that
you have to go back and break this
elliptic curve mission was done either
so this hashed version is a very very
secure version of the public key so the
reason we create this is because all of
these batches of bitcoins they all gonna
contain a public key so this is just a
very safe version of the public key to
give away because it's hard to get back
to the private key so if there's gonna
be a sitting duck let's make it very
safe so there are two public key and
what we call this there's Nvidia
secretly a particularly a fancy name for
it we just called it the hash 160 of the
public key so they just hash because I'm
using hash functions and that last one
we use is to write BMD 160 so
it's commonly shortened to hash 160
public key so there we go so that's all
well and good we've hashed this but the
problem is now before we would have just
put the public key in here and in
created a signature and put that in
there but after a hash in this public
key you know there's no mathematical
connection you know from this hashed
version to the private key so we can't
just put a signature in here so when we
want to and send bitcoins what do we do
now
what we put in this space here this
unlocking code well we still put the
signature in here but along with the
signature we actually put in the public
key also so what that means is so this
lock now has adjusted a little bit to
say give me a public key and a signature
and what I'll do then is the first thing
you'll do is it will check that the
public key that you've put here hashes
to this hashed version of it you know
through this to it and anyone can do
that through these two hash functions
and after - after doing that it will do
what it did before just sack check that
the signature works so whereas before we
had the public key in here and there's
like a one step process of comparing the
signature to the public key this is now
a two step process where it first
compares the public key to the hashed
version that you've given away and if
that checks out they will check the
signature against the public key so
basically just adds another step okay go
on
so in that sense we do have public keys
which are for the Asch 160s that is open
information yes if I okay another
question point that you'd be thinking
now is okay well what's the point in
hash in this and giving this away if
eventually we're going to be given the
public key away anyway
well the thinking is that this public
key and
is only given away at the last moment so
say it took some time to be able to you
know brute force and get backwards
through this elliptic curve that if it
was broken in some way well if it was
first of all if it's completely broken
then your bitcoins are safe so if you
just don't spend them then they're still
no one else can take them but they're
not obviously not very good but this
developed the thinking is that this is
like you only give away at the last
moment and if it's given away the last
moment then hopefully other people won't
have the time to be able to work
backwards quick enough to be able to
steal your bitcoins but on the plus side
well is I think it's better than nothing
really so this is why we use this hash
version so this hashed version you know
it doesn't give anyone any incentive to
try and work backwards through this I
have to give because I have to get
through these first so it's busy going
somewhere my thought is that let's say
we have ten bitcoins behind this work
yes yeah and we spend say one Bitcoin
out of those term declines so at this
time an attacker has the public key for
the hash 160 yes but what you boo and
yeah but what you do is say you want to
send a sin is 10 bitcoins here and we
want to send one Bitcoin to someone else
and then we want to keep the change for
ourselves what is recommended is that
you create a new address so that's why
everyone says don't reuse the same
address that's because when you send the
change to yourself if you use a
different address then even though you
give them away there's public key it's
effectively useless because all of the
bitcoins that were locked to this public
key and I've been spent and moved on so
that's why everyone says to not to use
different address or to use different
addresses every time for your change
right yeah then the last-minute logic
makes sense that is because if it's a
new address then again you don't know
the public Yeah right
so in kalameet sense but so obviously
now you can still use if you go back you
can still use this method I've just put
in the public key in here and you can
still create locks that do this and that
is perfectly fine but when people all of
the wallets these days they all built to
use this to hash vision the public key
because it's more secure but you can
still use this you know put a public key
in here and then just use one signature
that's how a lot of early transactions
in the blockchain if you check them out
they use a very simple public key and
one signature but all the transactions
now well you know more recent ones they
use the hash hashed version inside this
lock and then they put the public key
and signature in the unlocking code
afterwards so by here I've just done a
wordy wordy description of how these
locks work the next video I'll do will
be actually looking inside these locks
to look at the code to see how they
actually work so this is the locking
code the lock and this is the unlocking
code here so okay finally like I said
what is an address I have to go through
this just to show you an address comes
from so like I said in the last one and
maybe want to receive bitcoins we give
away this hashed version of the public
key but if you actually look at all this
data so let's say this is a private key
and then this is a public key which is a
big number as well these were typically
stored in hexadecimal format so let me
just convert those quickly and so many
hash all this data through those two
hash functions we end up with this
hexadecimal number here for that hashed
version of the public key this works and
we can give this way to other people
that's fine
there's no this is if you wanted to make
it simple you could just give people
this direct hashed version the public
key and that's fine but the problem is
it's not particularly user friendly
because so you give it away or you
describe the this public key over the
phone say someone else types it in and
they make a mistake and then they fill
it out if they make one single mistake
then it's gonna send the Bitcoin so
different completely different address
so it's going to lose those bitcoins and
this person is not going to receive them
so that's not good so there's no error
checking so when you type in this hashed
version the public key there's no way to
check it for errors secondly it's a bit
long so if you make it shorter that'd be
great but it's importantly there's no
way we check in so what can we do to
make these well basically the address is
just going to be a you more
user-friendly version of this public key
that contains error checking and it's a
bit shorter so how do we fix this error
checking problem well what we do is you
we create what's called a checksum so we
hash this hashed version of the perfect
key and that will give us a long number
if we just take the four bytes the first
four bytes of that the hash of this
public key and that is called the
checksum and so we stick that on the end
and so what that means is if someone was
to type in this whole entire public key
into their wallet software if they make
one mistake here the wallet software can
hash this and check to make sure for
this part of the key matches the
checksum and if it doesn't then they'll
know someone's made a mistake somewhere
they won't be you want be able to tell
you where it's made a mistake but it
will note it will say wait there
you made mistake here some man which is
better than nothing
similarly like I said it's a bit long
can we make this any shorter no I've got
the checksum here Smith the public key a
bit longer again can we shorten it down
well yes we can this version here has
been encoded in a hexadecimal format
which contains has 16 characters to
choose from
what if it's just a number instead of in
chord encoding it in a format there used
to 16 characters well if we just use a
lot more characters so it's a 16
characters here what if you use the
entire alphanumeric alphabet which has
six new characters if we can start using
these then we can represent this number
in a much shorter space with a lot less
characters problem with use in all of
these characters is some of them a bit
awkward type out you know like zeros and
all look the same
so we don't want to use those similarly
similarly an L and a big are you can
look the same so we don't wanna use
those either so if you just kick those
out we're left with 58 characters to
choose from so when you're encoding
numbers in a particular format and the
number of characters you have to choose
from is also known as the base so this
is base 16 and this is base 58 base 58
is just the alphanumeric alphabet our
characters with the awkward ones taken
out so what you do if you just take all
this data this public key with a check
sum at the end and you encode it in this
format using be a fifth base 58
characters you get something a little
bit shorter and a bit more slightly more
user-friendly but most importantly you
know it has this arrow tracking
capability and that's why you'll often
see addresses in this particular format
hopefully this looks a little familiar
so basically it's just basically eight
and this is what we call the address so
the address is just the pretty version
of this hashed public key there we are
so we give there so instead of given the
hashed version away we could give the
hashed version away away if we wanted to
that's perfectly fine but you know with
wallets these days everyone asked for an
address so you give the address away and
that means if they type it in and they
type it in wrong the wallet software can
say wait there something's not right so
it's more user-friendly it's used to use
this address or safer to do so just to
clarify you can easily go backwards and
forwards you know encode in a base 58
this isn't using any particular hash
function all it's doing it's just
converting from one number format to
another you know like converting from
decimal to hexadecimal that's one number
conversion but they're still seen the
number convicted they're still the same
number ultimately and you can go back
and forth between hexadecimal base 16
base 58 you can go back and 4 again so
what that means is when you do actually
give a address or type 1 into a wallet
while the wallet does when it creates
transaction it just works out what the
hash to public key is and then it'll put
that as the lock so even though you you
input a an address the wallet will
convert it to this and hashed version so
if you look at the blockchain there are
none aren't any actual addresses on the
blockchain in the locks at least it's
just the hashed version of the public
keys on the blockchain or inside the
transaction data so does that make sense
ok great
lastly some code examples so if all this
makes sense you understand how keys and
addresses work so you have the basic
private key and public key which is
basics needed for sending and receiving
transactions then you create digital
signatures so that we can prove they'll
be on a public key that the private key
is that while we can prove that we
created the public key
from a private key but I would actually
ever having to give away the private key
and that's how the transaction system
works creating digital signatures
finally we made a dress gone okay
actually all transaction data have
public keys and yes the address is just
like two of the the user-friendly top
layer but inside actual transactions or
they use is the public key and the
hashed public key the address is just
for user-friendly purposes so okay so if
you understand all that then you
understand how a keys and addresses work
in this final part now just went through
quite quickly not too complex just how
you can generate your own set of keys
and addresses I think this is quite fun
to do it's not terribly hard you know
take some coding but you can actually
easily create your own set of keys so
you can send and receive bitcoins and
it's quite a fun thing to do if you want
to get started working a Bitcoin so I'll
just show you now all the technical
stuff how to actually create your own
set of keys start with a private key so
let me just move this across make that
bit bigger so first of all let's see you
doing some programming and you want to
create your own statically generate your
own set of keys you first of all start
by generating a private key and if you
remember a private key just a random
number the most important thing we're
generating this random number is that
you use a secure source of randomness
this is the most important part by far
make sure it's secure
don't just use the standard random
number generators in your programming
language they're probably not secure
enough for this kind of stuff so good
sources of randomness as far as I'm
aware is using the open SSL library
every programming language so that
should have access to it or sorry or if
you're on Linux use dev read bytes from
dev you random that should be random
enough for you
alternatively if you just have a Googler
around for your programming language
there should be a library that gives you
quick and easy access to these two
things if they're available so in Ruby
it's called secure random not sure it is
in other languages but just have a look
around for the most secure source of
randomness in your programming language
it's very important so again okay so you
are secure a source of randomness you
need to generate a 256 bit number so
that's between one and a number that is
2 to the power of 256 which in decimal
is this but to be precise it's actually
the range of valid private keys is
slightly less than this and that's
because of the limitations of the
particular the particular curve used in
Bitcoin in this cave it has a parameter
called n which is just the number of
points on the curve and you cannot
exceed this for your private key and
it's only actually a little bit smaller
than 2 to the power of 256 it's very
close to it but just to be sure I don't
even see this number changing but this
is 2 2 power of 56 but this is the N or
the number of points on the curve so
make sure it's below this and if you
google around the name of the curve SEC
P 2 5 6 K 1 you can find the parameter
for n so there we are we just generate a
random number we can show us below this
maximum value here so that's the private
key done just generate a random number
secondly now we want to create the
public key we need to use the elliptic
curve this one and actually we do need
to do implicit elliptic curve
multiplication but actually in your
programming language there probably is a
library that gives you access to and if
to give stuff so you can just include
that in and just ask it to do some
implicit multiplication so you draft a
code in this for yourself you can just
get a librarian
do it for you so what you do is just to
indicate multiplication multiply this
generator point or this value and I'll
bounce on the cave and the final resting
point will be this public key and the
public key is the ax and y value at this
point obviously this public key is quite
large we've got to 256 bit numbers here
so that's gonna take up a lot of space
and ID be in Bitcoin because the
blockchain is a shared file we don't be
taking up too much space if we don't
have to so what we can do we can
actually shrink this number down a
little bit and we can do that because
one of the handy properties are this
elliptic curve is that it's symmetrical
along the x-axis so what that means is
if you have an x value then it's only
the Y value it's only gonna be one of
two different values so for every x
value there's only two given Y values so
you could think about being Y or minus y
and one of the handy properties of this
elliptic curve is that if this Y value
is even then it means it's it's one it's
one point on the curve say this one or
if it's odd it means it's the other
point on the curve so I mean when we
want to store this public key we don't
have to store the full Y value all we
need to know is whether it's even or odd
so this Y value here is even so all we
need to know just always full public key
is that it's even a name we can figure
out what it was from there based on the
x value so this is the x value and then
we can just put the whether the Y is
even or odd at the front obviously you
don't put the word even at the front or
odd there are two codes for that so if
it's e if it's even but o2 like so or if
it's odd over 3 and early on in Bitcoin
public keys were actually stored using
both the x and y value and these are
called uncompressed keys so this is a
compressed key because you don't use the
full y value because we don't need to
but this wasn't known by satoshi at the
start that you could compress them so a
lot of early on bit in any public keys
use the uncompressed format and if you
want to use number cut price for Matt
that'll start with over four zero four
sorry but this one zero two so there we
go that is the public key just in the X
x coordinate and whether the Y is even
or odd encoded as a zero two or zero
three don't need to convert all this tax
decimal i've been showing this in
numbers just to illustrate that this is
all just numbers but when you come to
look at private keys and public keys or
pass them around
they're usually stored in hexadecimal
format so there we go that's private key
is 32 bytes and this public key should
be future by it's also quick tip if this
public key it's quite a low number and
when you convert it into hexadecimal if
it's not 32 pipes in length make sure to
pad it out at the start with the zeros
to make sure the whole xx value part of
the public key is 32 bytes altogether so
just a quick tip otherwise you'll end up
creating an incorrect address later on
so okay that's the basics done private
key random number public key just
develop two key of multiplication and
store the Y value in a compressed format
we just need to know with it if it's
even or odd now we've got that we just
put that through two hash functions
because now you want the Hat to hash 160
of this to give a way to other people so
if we just put it through sha-256 first
then wipe mt 160 and that gives you this
digest this result
don't forget when you're hashing in
Bitcoin to configure this to binary
first before you put into the hash
function and a spirit of binary result
put that binary result into the next one
I'll spit up binary thank averted to
taxes a hexadecimal and this is that
gives you this hash one-sixth
here you might notice that this result
this digest is a bit smaller than these
32 byte public keys
that's because char 256 is 256 bits
produces 256 bit results which is 32
bytes but right the MT 160 produces
smaller results 160 bit digests which is
20 bytes so that's quite a bit smaller
like so fine okay
so this is what we give way to other
people this is the protected public key
if you will but now we want to create
the address which is like a prettier
version with some error checking
involved so what we do we need some base
58 this but before we do that we first
of all put a version byte at the start
which for most addresses is 0 0 I'll
explain why we do that in just a moment
and then like I said earlier we need a
checksum so we just hash all of this so
the public key with a version by at the
start hash at all here's the checksum
hash it twice you know like in mining
then we take the first four bytes last
to checksum that's all we need really to
be sure enough that this hash is
correctly for the error tracking and
then we put all that then through base
58 so public key well the hashed version
of it vision byte at the start check
them at the end stick it all through
base 58 and that would give us this
address the reason be append or prepend
sorry
this version byte at the start is
because it effects the leading character
of the address after weaving codes it in
base 58 format so for normal addresses
where we just want to send and receive
bitcoins in a typical way
we put zeros you at the start and that
gives us a one address so that means
that you just want to send and receive
bitcoins in typical way so if by
changing this version byte at the start
it changes the starting character of the
address so 0 0 is for typical sending or
receiving addresses on the on the main
net network but for test NAT so if
you're on a test net network you put 6 F
at the start and that will change the
leading character so there are quite a
few of these different version bytes of
the start to give you different
addresses but for most cases you're just
gonna use 0 0 to give you a 1 address
yes so I think I'll cover this a bit
more in the locking code or script video
which will be coming up after this one
but for most addresses just one stick
and zeros you at the start so there we
go that's how you create you can create
your own set of keys just through this
process here hopefully you all made some
sense or it's cleared up some issues so
there we go any questions about that
okay okay
just a quick question you mentioned
something about 32 bytes riding or some
yes okay okay um I probably do need to
mention that but when you private keys
and public keys
well this x coordinate is always 32
bytes and private keys or 32 bytes as
well and just a little tip that if you
when you do this lipstick you have
multiplication so you get a small number
for X and then you convert it to
hexadecimal then you might end up
getting a hexadecimal number that isn't
32 bytes long if that's the case just be
sure to pad it up and 0 to the start so
that the each X so the x coordinate is
the right length because that's
important because if you missed out a
character here that when they should
have been a zero there then this is
going to hash out to a different value
so you'll be sending bitcoins to the
wrong place so it's just I've made this
mistake before so I just wanted to bring
it up to make sure that no one else
makes the same mistake so there we go
and that's how to create your own
addresses and private keys and whatnot
so that's that part and my to know here
we go so I've made a little script here
it's written in Ruby and that will
create a set of keys tries to go through
an order it starts off by generating a
private key
just getting a secure random number the
maximum is this value here which is n
like I said earlier which is the number
of points on the curve so if asked to
big I'll just raise an error so that
generates a private key
after that he need to go from the
private to the public so we just use the
elliptic curve you do his ed up to give
multiplication
and then you that give you an x and y
value so in the old format it's just the
x and y but a new format if want to
compress the public key
you just take whether Y is even or odd
and then / - no - or no three at the
start based on that after the public key
you only get the hash 160 it's quite
simple just put it through two different
hashing functions so sha 256 and then
wipe MD 160 and then to get the address
you stick a prefix of the start create a
checksum by hashing the hash 160 and
then the address is just all about
encoded in base 58 so if you have some
utility functions like the base 58 and
stuff and there we are so here's the
code you just run Ruby key generator
I'll put this code on the website or a
link in the description and this will
give you a set of keys as you can see
it's quite fast so even though we did
all this you know crazy elliptic curve
multiplication when you run the code
it's pretty fast to give you you know
your psyches so just to prove to you um
here's an address I can send some
bitcoins there's a debt this address may
be our nest and the base description
sorry me not just for just to show up
send a low fee send
okay so the paper has been sent so copy
that I'm sorry maybe our browser send
the transaction look at the transaction
right there it is
so Wendy 9 that's the address I sent it
to so like I said earlier remember how
the electrum Wallace took care of my
change form for me and it sent it to a
different address like here so the
public here is protected okay a few
quick tips just before I go and this is
a very good graphical address generator
that shows you all the steps you need to
do to generate your own addresses if you
go on the Royal Fork blog Google that
cool and gone to the graphical address
general address generator it's very good
so if you're programming and you want to
create your own set of keys and
addresses this is very very helpful
it's helped me a lot it's very good
secondly and preset about you've got all
those different caves and you know the
SEC p25 6k one well they're all outlined
on the SEC website so here's a I put a
link in the description
here's the you are so here's the
parameters for that cave so you have
lots different caves but this is just
the one that Bitcoin uses that one so
yep there we go
one last thing don't forget for these
private keys
you also have lost like an address
version like a pretty version the
private key which is called wallet
import format I haven't covered it here
but it's very similar to this process
for getting a pretty version at the
public key so if you ever see wallet
import format it's just the pretty
version of the private key any questions
I'm glad it all made sense
I tried to make it as a flowing as
possible because it's quite a lot I
thought with the elliptic curves and
stuff to include that I don't cover how
that all works I just wanted to cover
the basics of keys what are you yeah and
yeah yeah no I felt like that I felt
that as well when I was doing the video
I was like oh god this is quite a lot of
information it's hard to you know do
it's hard to take it all in one sitting
but maybe if you want to learn yeah yeah
it's just numbers I think if you just
went through this process of creating
your own set of keys I think you'd learn
everything as you went along but
hopefully this gives you a primer to get
going I suppose and create them